I run a Youtube channel and website called SpareCash.se and I started it in 2016.
I became a millionaire as a 27-year-old, it's such a title that newspapers and everything else love to flag with.
Then it goes up and down as you understand, the stock market turns a lot.
But my channel anyway, it has 43,500 subscribers, a thousand views about every day.
Overall, over 3.3 million views on the channel.
And I have about 500-1000 views on my website at sparecash.se every day.
So it is so that you want to learn more about the basics because today we will run about an hour and a half.
So this channel is great, I think.
But I'm a little biased in this then.
But there are a lot of people who appreciate it anyway, as you can see, I'm the biggest in finance on Youtube,
As privately owned then, which is not run by Handelsbanken or something like that.
And it is a project called Young Private Economics.
And then you go through these grounds, shares, funds, savings, pensions and stuff in a short time.
Meanwhile, I traded and played Allan Ballan on the stock exchange as a 19-year-old.
And lost quite a lot of money.
20,000 on turbocharges, which I heard here, in just over two hours.
And then I got a mindset and thought it is better to do something with the money
Instead of just sitting and playing with them to make them try to grow.
So I booked a trip to Thailand, to Bangkok.
And then I was away, there I was a little more fit.
Snorkeled with whale sharks in the Philippines and got some other thoughts of life.
I was in Australia too and saw these cute Wallabies.
But while I was in Australia, I got a mindset
And I wrote in my notepad on the computer.
Start Your Own Shit.
And it was there that, like the foundation for Sparecash, started.
So I came home and started knocking code, programming and building sparecash.se.
And that was the foundation.
And it is 2016 and today I live on this.
Therefore, it is important when choosing shares.
That you look at them.
And we will come in on a few different pieces.
How to avoid them.
To filter out such companies.
Which can potentially go bankrupt.
It is by far the worst outcome.
When we invest.
If a company goes bankrupt.
Then we lose all our money.
There is no value left then.
If you choose to join SAVR and are a member.
If you are not members then you can become members
And then you automatically get SEK 300 to save for in SAVR.
More information on the membership page, the share savers.
Yes, they can talk to you then after.
SAVR is good and there you get 300 bucks with the share savers and membership.
When you invite friends you get 100 bucks.
Because I have Instagram account.
Unfortunately, now they have limited it.
Back in the days then, I think I got 5,000.
You can invite friends and get 100 SEK.
Then you get part of.
Then you buy several of these.
Great fund.
I will show it later.
But also.
The investment companies have a lower fee.
Than the funds have.
Great.
Exactly.
You can buy a fund.
Called Spiltan's investment company.
And get all of them here.
But then it costs a fee every year.
To own that fund.
So it is cheaper instead to buy these investment companies
and make "your own fund".
Okay, one last then.
So the investment companies are so good.
Start in funds.
Then you can save, for example, Avanza a penny.
Maybe a hundred kronor per month.
And then you spread the risk in several other companies.
But it's not just the best friend of the small saver.
It is also the bank's cashier.
Just as you mentioned.
After all, there are funds that banks make a lot of money from.
And that is through fees then.
And we get that right away.
But when you save in funds, set up an automatic monthly savings.
Then I do not mean specifically this fund
Without some benchmarks.
I have funds that cost more than one percent per year.
But try when you are new to avoid them.
Until you know if they are worth that fee.
So benchmarks, avoid funds with one percent in fee and up.
Fund in fund solutions.
This means that the fund has funds in itself.
If you are on the Avanza app or on your computer.
So you can scroll down a bit.
Under the fund and then you see the holdings
And there are a lot of funds in there.
I hope no one works at Maxmathiessen or Söderberg Partners.
But they have a tendency to do.
They have a tendency to buy funds in their funds.
Which means you receive a fee on the fee.
So you pay a double fee.
And also in the pension for example.
So it may be that you have a fee for the entire pension savings.
So you who have an occupational pension.
Check out your occupational pensions.
There may be very hidden fees.
Which you don't think about.
If you don't know what you are doing.